<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>CouchDB - Tag - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://kalali.blog/tags/couchdb/</link>
        <description>CouchDB - Tag - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kalali.blog/tags/couchdb/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Getting started with CouchDB and MongoDB, Part II: Beginning with Security</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2013/09/2013-09-17-getting-started-with-couchdb-and-mongodb-part-ii-beginning-with-security/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2013/09/2013-09-17-getting-started-with-couchdb-and-mongodb-part-ii-beginning-with-security/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the first part of this series I discussed how can we perform CRUD operation in MongoDB and CouchDB. In this part we will look into security features of MongoDB and CouchDB. In the next two installments of this series I will go into how to apply the configuration that are described here and how to write codes that work with them.
Basic security requirements There are some basic features and functionalities which are required by different applications, in addition to tons of other more advanced fine grained features, which one can expect a semi-structured data storage server to provide.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting started with CouchDB and MongoDB, Part I: CRUD operations</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2013/09/2013-09-12-getting-started-with-couchdb-and-mongodb-nosql-document-databases-part-i/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2013/09/2013-09-12-getting-started-with-couchdb-and-mongodb-nosql-document-databases-part-i/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In a series of blog I am going to write to cover CouchDB and MongoDB as two popular document databases. In each one of the entries I will show how can you do similar tasks with each one of these two so that you get some understanding of the differences and similarities between them. I am not going to do any comparison here but reading the series you can draw conclusion on which one seems more suitable for your case based judging by how different tasks can be accomplished using these two.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
