<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>microservices - Tag - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://kalali.blog/tags/microservices/</link>
        <description>microservices - Tag - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 17:50:55 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kalali.blog/tags/microservices/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Microservices Runtime Fragmentation</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2022/07/microservices-fragmentation-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 17:50:55 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2022/07/microservices-fragmentation-and-what-to-do-about-it/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/post-img/microservices-fragmentation-and-what-to-do-about-it.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Fragmentation of Java runtimes in a microservices-based architecture There are many many differences between the monolithic architecture and microservices-based architecture. One of them is the number of independently deployed bits of software, with a monolith there are usually many replicas of the same distribution running on many machines, virtualized or not. With the Microservices the number of independently deployed software systems grows as the different contexts raise&hellip; or an already existing context boundary grows enough to be split.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building a development platform</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2022/03/effective-internal-platform-product-manager/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 19:16:32 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2022/03/effective-internal-platform-product-manager/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/post-img/building-a-development-platform.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Intro Building a new development platform, for example a new microservices oriented platform to replace an existing monolith software system, is a massive endeavour. I have been working on a development platform, the whole ecosystem from ways of working to pipeline in the past 3 years and the experience might help others. So I thought to write down some of the observation and experience before they fully turn into intrinsic/implicit knowledge and hard to pen.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
