<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Architecture - Category - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://kalali.blog/categories/architecture/</link>
        <description>Architecture - Category - The Pensieve - Masoud Kalali&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>kalali@gmail.com (Masoud Kalali)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 20:16:32 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kalali.blog/categories/architecture/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Characteristics of a Good Observability Platform</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2023/01/characteristics-of-a-good-observability-platform/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 20:16:32 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2023/01/characteristics-of-a-good-observability-platform/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/post-img/characteristics-of-a-good-observability-platform.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction Observability is a critical pillar of operability in software systems. And the more complex the mesh of contributing components and infrastructure, the more important to have clear observability. The market for observability tooling is getting more mature with the explosion of the adoption of microservices and the standards for the interfaces are emerging with different vendors, adapting them at different levels.
Plenty of SaaS and on-premise products are around to buy and start using and almost all of them come with a 5 minutes demo to show how easy they are to use!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to plan the architectural attributes?</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2022/06/software-architecture-attributes-how-to-decide/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 20:45:02 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2022/06/software-architecture-attributes-how-to-decide/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/post-img/software-architecture-attributes-how-to-decide.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Last week I was talking to a former colleague, he is running a SaaS startup now, and our conversation went around SRE, production, and reliability. We talked a lot about architectural attributes that relate or impact the incidents, from detection to recovery, and on to prevention. I thought to put some of my thoughts around architecture into a blog post since that was the core of our conversation. The next post I will cover more details on architecture for fault tolerance.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Few tips for more success with architecture description</title>
    <link>https://kalali.blog/2022/04/few-tips-for-more-success-with-architecture-description/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 21:16:32 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Masoud Kalali</author>
    <guid>https://kalali.blog/2022/04/few-tips-for-more-success-with-architecture-description/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/post-img/few-tips-for-more-success-with-architecture-description.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction During the past 20 years I have seen trends come and go; one of the thing that has stayed around in one or another form is the term architecture and the architect role. Of course, there are plenty of overloads for the term and plenty of architect archetype like domain architect, enterprise architects, IT architect, network architect, software architect and you name it.
Wikipedia has a good definition of software architecture that I quote below:]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
